Register to The Ernest Trow Carter Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, 1894-1951; Series V; .8' (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence from Carter, V.A
    - United States. Library of Congress. Copyright Office., 1927-1933; 3 items (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Van Klenner, Katherine E., Baroness, 1924 Mar. 12; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Viafora, G., 1924 May 3; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Wagner, Oscar, 1942 Jan.-Jun.; 2 items (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Warner, Louise, 1931 May-Dec.; 3 items (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Watanabe, Ruth, 1951 Aug. 2-11; 2 items (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Watson, ? [Mrs.], 1922 Oct. 22; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Watt, Charles E., 1923-1933; 6 items (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Webb, Theodore, 1922 May 25; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Weed, Marion, 1924 Mar.-Apr.; 2 items (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Weekman, Louis E., 1916-1924; 6 items (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Western Music Library, 1924 Nov. 17; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Welch, R.D., 1939 Dec. 22; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Wetzel, Leroy Irving, 1923-1924; 4 items (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Witherspoon, Herbert, 1921-1922; 2 items (Box 35, Folder 28)
      see also Metropolitan Opera Association
    - Wright, Farnsworth, 1924 Mar. 17; 1 item (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Yale University Press, 1924 Feb.-Mar.; 3 items (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Ziegler, Edward, 1921-1922; 9 items (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified correspondence, 1920-1945; 8 items (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence to Carter, V.B
    - Agar, John G., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks
      see Hall, Edward Hagaman
    - Avril, Hans, 1927 Nov. 16; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Barrie, Helen, 1933 Apr. 27-29; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 31)
      Carter's reply on back
    - Bartholomew, Marshall, 1924 May 23; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Bauer, Flora, 1933 May 4-29; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Bevans, George E., 1949-1950; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Bogert, Walter L., 1922 May 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Bornschein, Edward, 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Borowsky, Serge, 1939 Jun. 28; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Bowles, Fred G., 1922 Feb.-Oct.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - B[--?], Elsa, 1927 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Boyd, Julian P., 1949 Nov.; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Briggs, Ernest, 1940 Jul. 31; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Brown, William
      see United States. Library of Congress. Copyright Office
    - Burrelle's Press Clipping Bureau, Inc., 1933 Jan. 6; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1924 Mar. 5; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Capital University Conservatory of Music
      see Crist, Wilbur E.
    - Carsner, Harriett, 1948 Jul. 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Carter, Alan, 1933 Apr. 25; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Carter, J.N. (Nelson), 1922 May 26; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Carter, Samuel T., Jr., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Chalmers, Thomas, ca. 1922 Jun. 8; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Craft, Marcella, 1939-1949; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Crist, Wilbur E., 1940 Mar.-Jul.; 5 items (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Curran, Charles C., 1922 May 23; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Cutter, James Bird, 1949 May 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Damrosch, Frank, 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - De[is?], Carl, 1922 Oct. 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Desellem, Domna [sic], 1938 Mar. 2; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - DeVoe, Elsie, 1924 Jan. 25; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Dippel, Andreas, 1914 Apr. 9; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Ditson, Alice M. (Mrs. Charles H.), 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Dodds, Harold W., 1934 Jun. 14-26; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Downes, Olin, 1928 Nov. 16; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Driggs, Spencer B., 1922-1933; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Duffield, Edward D., 1934 May-Jun.; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Eden, Hazel, 1924 Mar. 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Etude Music Magazine
      see Hipsher, Edward Ellsworth
    - Fessler, Otto, 1920-1924; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Forsyth, Holmes, 1924 Mar. 7; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Fortier, Florestine, 1922 Sep.-Oct.; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Foster, Bertha, 1949 Feb. 2; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Freer, Eleanor Everest (Mrs. Archibald), 1922-1924; 86 items (Box 36, Folder 35-36)
    - Frost, Bernice, 1933 May 2; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Furniss, Walter W., 1940 Dec. 1; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - G. Schirmer, Inc., 1903-1913; 5 items (Box 36, Folder 37)
      see also Reese, Gustave
    - Gaertner, ? [Dr.], 1927 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Gallagher, Charles E., 1922 Oct. 15; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Gerdau, Allan, 1927 Feb. 25; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Goldman, Edwin Franko, 1922 May 20-23; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Good, Marion B., 1924 Feb.-Mar.; 6 items (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Granberry, George Folsom, 1933 Jan. 5-28; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Grutzmacher, Mimi, 1927 Sep.-Nov.; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Hageman, Richard, ca. 1922 Apr. 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hall, Edward Hagaman, 1922 May 23; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hamlin, Anna M., 1922 Sep. 9; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hamlin, George, 1922 May 21, no date; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hadley, Henry, 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Harper, Henry S., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Harper, Katherine P., 1924 Jun. 3; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Haskell, William S., 1921 Mar. 7; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Herzog, Sigmund, 1920 Sep. 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hibben, John Grier, 1923-1932; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Hinshaw, William Wade, 1920-1922; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Hipsher, Edward Ellsworth, 1933 Jan. 24; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Hoe, Robert, 1927 Feb. 25; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Homaus, Loraine Van der pool, 1923 Sep. 10; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Hooker, Brian, 1922-1942; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Hurst, Edward R., [1922] May 24; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Hutcheson, Ernest, 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - International Publicity Service, 1923-1924; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Irvine, William Mann, 1903-1920; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Isaacson, Charles D., 1921-1922; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Jamison, Burdette [Mr. and Mrs. Burdette], 1949 Jul. 1; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Jillson, David C., 1931 Nov. 18; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Jones, Charles T.H., 1894-1927; 13 items (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Jones, Marged Edith, 1924 Feb.-May; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Judson, Arthur, 1924 Apr. 2; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Kahn, Otto, 1911-1924; 5 items (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Kaiden Studios, Inc., 1933; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Kramer, A.W., 1922 May 25; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - Kuecht, Joseph, 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 40)
    - La Forge, Frank, ca. 1936 Sep. 19; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Laliberte, Arthur, 1924 Oct. 16; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Le Massena, C.E., 1922 May 24; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Lilienthal, A.W., 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Linn, Katharine C., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Lockwood, Ethel?, 1903 May-Aug.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Lothar, Rud, 1912 May 11; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - Lund, Charlotte, 1933 Mar.-Apr.; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 41)
    - McAlpin, Charles W., 1922 May 24; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - McAlpin, D.H., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - McClure, Grace (Mrs. C.F.W.), 1922-1934; 17 items (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - [McClure?], Mac, 1933 Apr. 12; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 42)
    - McCormick, Cyrus H., 1924 Feb.-Mar.; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - [Mackay, Clarence H.], 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Madden, Myrtle Rudolph
      see Opera in Our Language Foundation, Inc.
    - Martens, Frederick H., 1924 Apr. 29; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Mason, William, 1900 Apr. 3; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Marvin, Dwight, 1948 May 11; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Metropolitan Opera Association, Inc., 1935 May 3; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
      see also Ziegler, Edward
    - Michaelis, Emil B., 1933 Jan.-Apr.; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Montgomery, James S., 1920 Jan.-Feb.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Morgan, Josephine P., 1922 May 23; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - Mullen, Grace, 1942-1949; 8 items (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Music News, 1924 Mar. 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 44)
      see also Watt, Charles E.
    - Musical Advance
      see Driggs, Spencer B.
    - Musical America
      see Fessler, Otto; Kramer, A.W.; and Swaab, M.B.
    - Musical Leader, 1924 Jan. 4; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 44)
      see also Bauer, Flora; and Smith, Evelyn French
    - Musical Observer
      see Saenger, Gustav
    - Musicians Club of America
      see Foster, Bertha.
    - Mussey, Kendall K., 1931-1932; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 44)
    - Nevin, Arthur, 1924 Feb.-Sep.; 5 items (Box 36, Folder 45)
    - New York Opera Comique, no date; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 45)
      see also Mussey, Kendall K.; and Shearon, Marjorie
    - Opera in Our Language Foundation, Inc., 1923 Sep.-Dec.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 46)
      see also Freer, Eleanor Everest (Mrs. Archibald); and Yager, Narcissa H. (Mrs. Louis E.)
    - Outlook Company, ca. 1924 Dec.; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Panenko, Antoni, 1931 Sep. 19; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Patton, Fred, 1922 May-Jul.; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Players, 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
      1949 Oct. 11
    - Price, Lucker E., 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - P[--?], L.F., 1922 May 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Princeton Club of Chicago, 1924 Feb. 5; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 46)
    - Redlands Communtiy Music Association, Inc., ca. 1949 Apr. 2; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
      see also Mullen, Grace
    - Reese, Gustave, 1943 Jan. 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - [Relman?], John, 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Rice, Edwin T., 1922 Oct. 31; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Rickett, Edward W., 1938 Jan. 31; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Rogers, Francis, [1922] May 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Russell, Alexander, 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 47)
    - Saenger, Gustave, 1922 May 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Schirmer, Rudolph E., 1903 Feb. 18; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Sealy, Frank L., ca. 1922 May; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Shea, George Edward, 1922 May 28; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Shearon, Marjorie, 1931 Sep.-Dec.; 4 items (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Simons, Theodor, 1927 Nov. 26; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Smith, Evelyn French, 1942 Apr.-May; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Smith, Harry B., 1908 Jun. 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Stidham, Everton E., 1943 Mar. 19; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Strong, John, 1943 Jan. 5; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Stuart, James E., 1924 Feb. 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Svecenski, Louis, ca. 1922 May; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Swaab, M.B., 1924-1933; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 48)
    - Talbot, Bryce, 1924 Mar. 10-11; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Tarkington, Booth, 1912 Feb. 9; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Thomas, Haydn Parry, 1924 Mar. 21; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - Triller, Charles, 1922 May 22; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - United States. Library of Congress. Copyright Office., 1927-1933; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - University Club. Club Activities Committee, no year Dec. 7; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 49)
    - University Glee Club of New York City
      see Haskell, William S.
    - Wagner, Oscar, 1941-1942; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Watanabe, Ruth, 1951 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Watt, Charles E., 1923 Dec. 24; 3 items (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Weed, Marion, 1924 Mar.-Apr.; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Welch, R.D., 1939 Nov. 20; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Wetzel, LeRoy, 1924 Apr. 10; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Winkler, Albert, 1903 May 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 50)
    - Yager, Narcissa H. (Mrs. Louis E.), 1922 Mar.-May; 2 items (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Yeomans, Edward, 1935 Aug. 13; 1 item (Box 36, Folder 51)
    - Ziegler, Edward, 1920-1922; 10 items (Box 36, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence between Others, V.C
    - Miscellaneous correspondence between others, 1912-1974; 8 items (Box 36, Folder 52)
- Programs, 1897-1974; Series VI; .4' (1 box)
  The programs are arranged alphabetically by title of the musical work, with church service programs, miscellaneous works, and music by others, at the end. Within each of these entries, the programs are arranged chronologically. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series.
  - Andante and Scherzo, 1901-1950; 7 items (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Blonde Donna, 1912-1949; 12 items (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Namba, 1924-1933; 8 items (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Quartet, strings, no. 1, G major, 1934-1935; 2 items (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - White Bird, 1922-1939; 10 items (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Includes manuscript program notes
  - Church service programs, 1948-1974; 6 items (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous works, 1897-1942; 10 items (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Music by others, 1931-1932; 7 items (Box 37, Folder 8)
- Clippings, Press Notices, and Advertisements, 1897-1949; Series VII; .8' (2 boxes)
  This series is divided into two subseries: A. Clippings; and B. Press Notices and Advertisements. The items are arranged alphabetically by the title of the musical work with miscellaneous musical works and clippings at the end. Items are filed chronologically within each entry. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series, with oversized items housed at the end of the collection (Box 44).
  - Clippings, VII.A
    - Blonde Donna, 1908-1949; 557 items (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
    - Namba, 1924-1933; 25 items (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - White Bird, 1922-1941; 296 items (Box 38, Folder 8-12)
      Foreign clippings in folder 10
    - Miscellaneous musical works by Carter, 1935-1947; 42 items (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1910-1944; 196 items (Box 38, Folder 14-16)
  - Press Notices and Advertisements, VII.B
    - Blonde Donna, 1912-1941; 28 items (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Blonde Donna, 1912-1941; 3 items (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Namba, 1933; 7 items (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - White Bird, 1922-1939; 26 items (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - White Bird, 1922-1939; 1 item (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous musical works by Carter, 1897-1915; 4 items (Box 38, Folder 20)
- Photographs, 1888-1941; Series VIII; 1.25' (3 boxes)
  The photographs are divided into three subseries. The first, A. Carter Alone and with Others, is arranged chronologically with photographs from Carter' Princeton '88 yearbook at the end. The second subseries, B. Individuals, is arranged alphabetically by name, with unidentified photographs at the end. The final subseries, C. Stage Works, is arranged alphabetically by title, and then chronologically by production. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series, with oversized photographs housed at the end of the collection (Box 44).
  - Carter alone and with others, VIII.A
    - Carter alone, 1892-1927 or 1929
      - Carter alone, 1892-1927 or 1929; 37 items (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
      - Carter alone, 1892-1927 or 1929; 1 item (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Princeton '88 yearbook, 1888
      The yearbook was disassembled and the individual photographs of classmates were sent to Princeton University
      Includes 2 duplicate photographs not bound with the yearbook
      - Princeton '88 yearbook, 1888; 27 items (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
      - Princeton '88 yearbook, 1888; 6 items (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Carter and family, 1941 Sep. 28; 5 items (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Individuals, VIII.B
    - Altenbach, Dora, 1927 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Avril, Hans, 1927-1928; 2 items (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - B--?, Elsa, 1927 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Carter, Aaron, no date; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Carter, Laura Hoe, no date; 2 items (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Hooker, Brian, 1917?; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, Edwin, 1936 Dec.; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Hummelsheim, Karl, no date; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Note enclosed
    - Liebscher, Maria, 1927 Nov. 15; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Liebscher, Otto, 1927 Nov. 30; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Bette, 1940 Feb.; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Duane and Dale, 1939; 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified family member in front of house identified as Carter's birthplace no date, 1 item (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Stage Works, VIII.C
    - Blonde Donna
      - New York Opera Comique, 1931
        - New York Opera Comique, 1931; 19 items (Box 39, Folder 9)
        - New York Opera Comique, 1931; 3 items (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Redlands, California, 1937
        - Redlands, California, 1937; 13 items (Box 39, Folder 10)
        - Redlands, California, 1937; 1 item (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - Riverside, California, 1941; 4 items (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Unidentified productions, no date
        - Unidentified productions, no date; 2 items (Box 39, Folder 12)
        - Unidentified productions, no date; 4 items (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Namba
      - Columbus School for Girls, 1924; 4 items (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Stamford, Connecticut, 1930; 4 items (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - [Shakespeare Theatre, New York?], [1933]; 3 items (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Natoma, no date
      Note from envelope: pictures by Louise Moseley
      - Natoma, no date; 4 items (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - Natoma, no date; 1 item (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - White Bird
      - [Carnegie Hall], [1922]; 6 items (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - Osnabrück, 1927
        Includes 5 glass plate negatives
        - Osnabrück, 1927; 22 items (Box 39, Folder 18)
        - Osnabrück, 1927; 5 items (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - [Hudson Theatre], 1937; 4 items (Box 40, Folder 20)
      - Riverside, California, 1939
        - Riverside, California, 1939; 10 items (Box 40, Folder 21)
        - Riverside, California, 1939; 16 items (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, ca. 1929-1930; 2 items (Box 40, Folder 23)
- Writings, 1911-1942; Series IX; .4' (1 box)
  The writings are divided into three subseries: A. By Carter, these are arranged chronologically; B. By Others, arranged alphabetically by author; and C. Lists and Catalogues, arranged chronologically. They include holograph, manuscript, typescript, and published articles, poems, books, brochures, lists, and catalogues. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series.
  - Writings by Carter, IX.A
    - Re: opera in English at the Century Opera House, 1914 Oct. 13; 1 item; 4 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "A Brief Sketch of Organized Music at Princeton from the Time of Langlotz to the Present", 1924; 1 item; 3 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Ernest Carter - Composer", ca. 1934 Feb. 16; 1 item; [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Opera Comique in America", no date; 1 item; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Typescript, signed
    - "The Use of a Concert Program Analysis", no date; 1 item; 3 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Re use of the word "pantomime", no date; 1 item; 2 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Typescript with ink additions
    - "Deadly Parallel: Natoma + The Blonde Donna", no date; 1 item; 3 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous jottings and lists, 1922-1942; 7 items (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Writings by Others, IX.B
    - Popular Guide to the Words and Music of Aida / Century Publishing Co. -- New York: Century Opera House, c1913., Century Publishing Company; 1 item; 23 p.; 18 cm. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Rejected / by Carrie Coal. -- no date, Coal, Carrie; 1 item; [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Old Nassau / Edited and Published by Wilfred Seymour Conrow.-- New York City: s.n., 1905., Conrow, Wilfred Seymour; 2 items; 66 p.; 25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Includes arrangements of "Old Nassau" by Carter
      Two copies, one is a signed presentation copy with note from Conrow enclosed
    - Ours is a finding faith/ By Frank Gannett. -- no date, Gannett, Frank; 1 item; 16 p.; 21 cm. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Pencil note by Carter on first page
    - New York Opera Comique / Yvette Guilbert ... [et. al.]. -- [S.l.: s.n., no date]., Guilbert, Yvette, 1865-1944; 1 item; 23 p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Privately published
    - Arbolada / By Harold G. Gulliver. -- [S.l.: s.n., no date]., Gulliver, Harold G.; 1 item; 20 p.; 36 cm. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Reprint from Country Life, 1924 Sep.
    - Double-sewed / Augustus Post. -- 1941 Dec. 8., Post, Augustus; 1 item; [1] sheet; 21 cm. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Printed copy of poem inscribed by author to Carter
    - Princeton in the World War, Princeton University. Office of the Secretary; 1 item; xxvii, 644 p.; 24 cm. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - University Library Finding list for the Music Library 1909. -- Princeton: University Library, 1909., Princeton University; 1 item; 93 p.; 25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Biographical articles re Carter and Brian Hooker and article re The Blonde Donna, 2 items; 2 items; 28 cm. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Typescripts
  - Lists and Catalogues, IX.C
    - Lists and Catalogues, 1911-1942
      Includes catalogue of Carter's music library, publishers's catalogues, lists of librettos owned by Carter, musical works, and Carter's musical works belonging to Elizabeth C. Richards
- Bills, Receipts, Contracts, and Certificates, 1898-1937; Series X; .4' (1 box)
  This series is arranged chronologically. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series.
  - Bills, Receipts, Contracts, and Certificates, 1898-1937; 13 items (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    Certificates of Carter's musical studies in Berlin, the Opera in Our Language Association, copyright registration, and of the awarding to Carter of the David Bispham Memorial Medal. Also includes bills and receipts for published music and performance expenses
- Memorabilia, 1881-1950; Series XI; .8' (2 boxes)
  The memorabilia are arranged chronologically. Boxes and folders are numbered consecutively throughout the series, with oversize materials housed at the end of the collection (Box 44).
  - Autograph album, 1941 May 20; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - "Phrenological character of Ernest T. Carter", 1883 Mar. 31; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook belonging to Carter's aunt, Laura Hoe, 1881-1950; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Postcards of Osnabrück, no date; 17 items (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Engraved copper plates, no date; 6 items (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Care Selve / Handel, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    1 sound disc: 78 rpm, mono.
    Performed by Mad. L. Fortier Housed at Historical Sound Recordings
  - Stage model for Namba made by Carter., no date; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Notes on back and laid in
  - Lithographic 1/2 tone cut mounted on a wooden block for the cover of the vocal score of The Blonde Donna, ca. 1936 Dec. 5; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Note: "Rec'd from C + C Music Printing Corp. + examined by E.C. Dec. 5/36"
  - Metal stamp with '88 insignia, no date; 1 item (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1905-1937
    - Miscellaneous items, 1905-1937; 10 items (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1905-1937; 1 item (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1905-1937; 1 item (Box 43)